寇克船长，我们相信你，但我们不会改变立场
We believe what you say, Captain Kirk, but our position has not altered.
哈克委员会不会允许
The Halkan Council cannot permit your Federation
联邦在这里开采双锂晶体
to mine dilithium crystals on our planet.
我们已向委员会证明这些任务是为了和平
We have shown the council historical proof that our missions are peaceful.
我们相信你的联邦目前是仁慈的
We accept that your Federation is benevolent at present,
但是未来无法预见
but the future is always in question.
双锂晶体力量惊人
Our dilithium crystals represent awesome power.
如果错误使用这种力量，即使只伤害一个人
Wrongful use of that power, even to the extent of the taking of one life,
也会违背我们和平处事的传统
would violate our history of total peace.
舰长，为了杜绝这种事，我们宁愿灭族
To prevent that, we would die, captain, as a race, if necessary.
我敬佩你高尚的品德
I admire your ethics
我们自己也很高尚
and hope to prove ours.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 我是史波克
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Spock here.
史波克先生，报告电磁风暴状况
Report on magnetic storm, Mr. Spock.
舰长，电磁风暴没有扩大，但是相当剧烈…
Standard ion type, captain, but quite violent...
并且不可预测
- and unpredictable.
- 传送危险吗？ - 是的，如果我们不尽早离开
- Rough ride? - If we stay.
准备回收地面队伍
Stand by to beam up landing party.
驾驶飞船到外层轨道上避免干扰，通话结束
Plot an extended orbit to clear disturbance. Kirk out.
- 苏鲁先生，执行命令 - 是的，长官
- Comply, Mr. Sulu. - Aye, sir.
我们什么时候能恢复谈判？
When may we resume discussion?
委员会会继续协商的，但是别抱希望
The council will meditate further. But do not be hopeful of any change.
舰长
Captain.
你可以逼我们交出晶体
You do have the might to force the crystals from us, of course.
但是我们不会那么做，好好考虑吧
But we won't. Consider that.
进取号，传送室，开始传送
Enterprise. Transporter Room, energise.
有麻烦了，长官
Trouble, sir.
史波克说对了，这真是次危险的…
Spock was right. It was a rough ri...
按照惯例，卡尔先生，半自动控制
At norm, Mr. Kyle. Controls at neutral.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
长官，任务执行的怎么样了？
Status of mission, captain?
- 没有进展 - 舰长，标准程序？
- No change. - Standard procedure, captain?
苏鲁先生，将相位炮对准哈克的城市
Mr. Sulu, you will program phaser barrage on Halkan cities.
是的，史波克先生
Yes, Mr. Spock.
- 舰长，他们的武装如何？ - 他们没有武装
- Their military capability, captain? - None.
真遗憾，这个星球上的人选择要自杀
Regrettable that this society has chosen suicide.
卡尔先生，遇到电磁风暴应该集中精神
Mr. Kyle, you were instructed to compensate during the ion storm.
- 但是我尽力了… - 漫不经心地操作设备
- But I tried... - Carelessness with the equipment
- 是不能容忍的 - 但是，史波克先生，我尽力了…
- cannot be tolerated. - But, Mr. Spock, I tried...
- 交出你的电击器 - 不，史波克先生
- Your agoniser. - No, Mr. Spock.
- 给我电击器 - 不，史波克先生
- Your agoniser, please. - No, Mr. Spock.
我尽力了，我真的尽力了
I tried, I really tried.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：sholto
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第四集
镜像世界
舰长日志，未知星历
Captain's log, stardate unknown.
在一场电磁风暴中，登陆队伍被传回进取号
During an ion storm, my landing party has beamed back to the Enterprise
但是发现飞船和上面的人员都变了
and found it and the personnel aboard changed.
飞船外型上也有了微妙的变化
The ship is subtly altered, physically.
行为和纪律也变得残酷、野蛮
Behaviour and discipline has become brutal, savage.
史考特，电磁暴对你的部门造成了轻微损伤
Mr. Scott, the storm has caused some minor damage in your section.
医生，有一些人员受伤，需要你关注
There are also injuries requiring your attention, doctor.
怎么样，先生们？
Well, gentlemen?
- 史波克先生 - 什么情况？
- Mr. Spock. - Yes?
长官，在登陆队伍被传送到飞船上时
The power beam jumped for a moment, sir,
能量流发生了短暂跳动
just as the landing party was about to materialise.
- 我从来没见过这种情况 - 这都是因为你的操作失误，卡尔先生
- I never saw it happen before. - Due to your error, Mr. Kyle?
不，史波克
No, Mr. Spock. Before.
舰长，这或许是电磁风暴太强烈导致的
Possibly a result of the severe storm. Captain.
- 你感觉到什么异常吗？ - 是的
- Do you feel any abnormal effects? - Yes.
麦考伊医生，最好给我们做一次彻底检查 这次传送很惊险
Dr. McCoy, you better look us over. That was a rough beam-up.
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
史波克先生，安排检查下传送装置是否正常
Mr. Spock, have those transporter circuits checked.
- 这是什么情况？ - 我们怎么会这样…？
- What is all this? - How did we get in this..?
现在不要讨论
Not now. Not now.
这是什么情况？
What is this?
所有事情都改变了，让人无法接受
Everything's all messed up, changed around, out of place.
舰长，到底发生了什么？
Captain, what's happened?
并不是所有事情，这个污点去年就有了
Well, not everything. That spot, I spilled acid there a year ago.
- 吉姆，这到底是…？ - 我不知道
- Jim, what in blazes..? - I don't know.
这确实是我们的进取号…
It's our Enterprise...
…但又不是
...but it isn't.
- 或许… - 或许什么，舰长？
- Maybe... - Maybe what, captain?
传送时你们有没有感觉到晕眩？
Any of you feel dizzy when we were in the transporter beam?
- 是的 - 当我们第一次实体化的时候呢？
- Yes. - When we first materialised?
- 我感觉到了 - 它发生了两次
- I did. - It happened twice.
我们先到了进取号，接着又被传送走了
First, we were in our own transporter chamber, and then we faded.
当我们最终实体化时，就到了这里
And then, when we finally materialised, we were here, wherever this is.
舰长，传送室的负责人提到过能量波动
Captain, the transporter chief mentioned a surge of power.
传送室或许受到电磁风暴的影响没有完全锁定我们
The transporter lock might have been affected by the ion storm,
我们被传送到了其他地方
and we just materialised somewhere else.
是的，这里
Yes, here.
不在我们的宇宙，不在我们的飞船上
Not our universe, not our ship.
有一些事情是…
Something...
…平行的
...parallel.
平行宇宙，在其他维度平面共存的宇宙
Parallel universe, coexisting with ours on another dimensional plane.
一切都被复制了
Everything's duplicated.
几乎所有事情
Almost.
另一艘进取号，长胡子的史波克…
Another Enterprise, Spock with a beard...
另一个寇克舰长，另一个麦考伊医生
Another Captain Kirk, another Dr. McCoy,
- 另一个… - 这是一次换位，如果我们到了这里…
- another... - An exchange. If we're here...
那这个宇宙的我们一定也在传送中
Then our counterparts must have been transporting up
在相同的时刻
at the exact same time.
在两个宇宙相似的风暴，都扰乱了设备运行
Similar storms on both universes disrupted the circuits.
我们到了这里，那他们…
We're here, and they're...
…一定在我们的进取号上
...on our Enterprise.
或许问着同样的问题：
Probably asking the same questions:
“我们在另一个宇宙吗？怎么才能回到原来的宇宙？”
"Are we in another universe? And if so, how do we get back to our own?"
他们会用电脑找出答案，我们也必须这么做
They'll use the computer, and we have to.
那哈克星人怎么办？
What about the Halkans?
我们不能让他们被毁灭
We can't let them be destroyed.
史考特，你能为我争取些时间吗？
Scotty, can you buy me some time?
到轮机室把主相位炮控制器短路
Get below and short out the main phaser couplings.
他们会认为是电磁暴损坏了电路
They'll think the storm blew the circuits.
- 好的，长官 - 然后，试试这台电脑吧
- Aye, sir. - Then, get on this technology.
如果我们想要回家，我们就必须这么做
It's all we have to work with if we want to get back home.
内部网络可能被监控了
The intercom may be monitored.
用你的联络器传送私人信息
Use your communicators for private messages.
- 使用子频率，防止被窃听 - 是，长官
- Sub-frequency, and scrambled. - Aye, sir.
- 上尉 - 是，长官
- Lieutenant. - Yes, sir.
回到你的岗位上去
Get up to your post.
查看今天舰队司令部发出的信息
Run today's communication from Starfleet Command.
我想知道我下过哪些命令
I want to know my exact orders, and options, if any.
- 是，长官 - 老骨头
- Yes, sir. - Bones.
舰长，我…我…
Captain, I... I'm...
乌乎拉，你是唯一能胜任的人，我稍后到指挥室
Uhura, you're the only one who can do it. I'll be right there.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
老骨头
Bones.
我们来看一下资料，我们有很多东西要学习
Let's take a look at the library. We have a lot to learn.
契诃夫先生，相位炮瞄准哈克行星上目标A
Mr. Chekov, phaser setting for planetary target A.
苏鲁先生，坐标712，打击力度4
Coordinates 712, stroke 4, Mr. Sulu.
发射电源锁定
Port batteries locked.
乌乎拉，还是对我不理不睬吗？
Still no interest, Uhura?
我会改变你的心意
I could change your mind.
长官，你擅离职守了
You are away from your post, mister.
舰长和史波克都不在
Is the captain here? Is Spock here?
山中无老虎…
When the cat's away...
- 报告通信状态 - 长官，没有受到风暴损坏
- Communication status. - No storm damage, sir.
所有部门都报告正常
All stations report normal.
你收到命令，如果哈克星人不妥协，就摧毁他们
You're ordered to annihilate the Halkans unless they comply.
必须执行
No alternative.
舰长，相位炮锁定目标A，正接近最佳攻击距离
Phasers locked on target A, captain. Approaching optimum range.
舰长，开火吗？
Commence fire, captain?
- 舰长？ - 原地待命，苏鲁先生
- Captain? - Stand by, Mr. Sulu.
我…
I...
我收到命令，过来检查相位炮组
I've been ordered to check phaser couplings
是否被风暴损坏了
for possible damage by the storm.
长官，你有安全部门的授权吗？
Do you have authorisation from Security, sir?
我接到的是舰长命令
Captain's orders.
长官，我必须向安全主管苏鲁核实
I'll have to check with Security Chief Sulu, sir.
不必了，我会向他说明的
Never mind, I'll attend to it.
- 我是寇克 - 长官，相位炮状况汇报，无损坏
- Kirk here. - Phaser report, sir. No damage.
非常好，谢谢，史考特先生，通话结束
Very good. Thank you, Mr. Scott. Kirk out.
行星自转正在使主目标脱离相位炮锁定
Planet's rotation is carrying primary target beyond arc of phaser lock.
需要我修正轨道到达新的发射位置吗？
Shall I correct orbit to new firing position?
不用
No.
- 锁定次要城市 - 是，长官
- Lock on to secondary city. - Aye, sir.
乌乎拉上尉，联络哈克星委员会，我想再次和他们对话
Lieutenant Uhura, contact the Halkan Council. I wish to talk to them again.
- 是，长官 - 舰长？
- Yes, sir. - Captain?
这是一个新的种族
This is a new race.
除了双锂晶体，他们还能提供其他珍贵的东西
They offer other things of value besides dilithium crystals.
但是，很明显，他们不愿意合作
But it is clear that we cannot expect their cooperation.
他们已经拒绝了帝国
They have refused the Empire.
我们接到的命令就是按照惯例摧毁哈克星
Command procedure dictates that we provide the customary example.
次要目标也脱离了相位炮锁定
Secondary target now moving beyond our phaser lock.
苏鲁先生，让相位炮待命
Put phasers on standby, Mr. Sulu.
- 舰长，这是严重违反命令的行为 - 我自有主张
- A serious breach of orders, captain. - I have my reasons.
当我有空了，会告诉你原因的
And I'll make them clear to you in my own good time.
舰长，哈克委员会的领导在B频道
Captain, I have the leader of the Halkan Council waiting on channel B.
抵抗是无用的
It is useless to resist us.
我们没有抵抗你
We do not resist you.
你有12个小时考虑后果
You have 12 hours to consider your position.
寇克舰长，即使12年或1万2千年
Twelve years, Captain Kirk, or 12,000.
我们基于道德的考虑
We are ethically compelled to deny your demand
拒绝给你提供双锂晶体
for our dilithium crystals,
因为你会用他们的力量去破坏
for you would use their power to destroy.
我们会夷平你的星球，得到我们想要的东西
We will level your planet, and take what we want.
那将是彻底的毁灭，你们整个种族都会灭绝
That is destruction. You will die as a race.
为了保持我们的人性，我们不惜一切代价
To preserve what we are.
谈判到此完毕，你只有12个小时
We will not argue. Twelve hours, no more.
关闭通话，关闭相位炮
Close communications, turn phasers off.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
舰长，你给他们12个小时，这是史无前例的
Twelve hours, captain. That is unprecedented.
我要到我的船舱去
I shall be in my quarters.
乌乎拉上尉
Lieutenant Uhura,
通知麦考伊医生和史考特先生到船舱见我
have Dr. McCoy and Mr. Scott meet me there.
舰长，你这是在自找麻烦
Captain, you've placed yourself in a most grave position.
我一定会报告你的所作所为
This conduct must be reported.
史波克先生，您请便
You're at liberty to do so, Mr. Spock.
长官，你要到5层吗？
Deck 5, sir?
你就要死了，舰长，我们都会升职的
So you die, captain, and we all move up in rank.
没有人会过问一个违背帝国意志的舰长
No one will question the assassination of a captain
是如何死的
who has disobeyed prime orders of the Empire.
舰长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplemental.
在我领导的进取号上
I command an Enterprise where officers apparently employ
长官们会从船员中雇佣私人追随者
private henchmen among the crew,
在这里，谋杀上级是晋升的常用手段
where assassination of superiors is a common means of advancing in rank.
我是你的人，舰长，放轻松，法瑞尔
Your men, captain. Easy, Farrell.
- 我替你们救了舰长，问问他吧 - 长官？
- I did your job. Ask the captain. - Sir?
是的，他确实救了我
Yes, he did your job.
聪明的家伙，懂得见风使舵
Smart boy. Switching to the top dog.
把他带走
Get him out of here.
长官，契诃夫先生答应让我做主管
Mr. Chekov was going to make me a chief, sir.
你也应该给我个官做做
You could make me an officer.
- 好的，你现在是我的人了 - 这是你的承诺吗？
- All right, you're working for me. - A commission?
你会晋升的，你甚至有可能当上舰长
You're in line. You might even make captain.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
但不是在我的船上
Not on my ship.
要对这个人用电击吗，长官？
The booth for this one, sir?
是的，电击，去吧
Yes, the booth. Carry on.
等等，这是什么？
Here. Here, what's this?
是血
It's called blood.
千万小心，这里的官员都是靠谋杀晋升的
Watch your step. The officers move up by assassination.
契诃夫就试图谋杀我
Chekov tried it on me.
苏鲁先生是安全主管，就像古代的盖世太保
Mr. Sulu is security chief, like the ancient Gestapo.
而我的医务室也变得非常恐怖
And my Sickbay is a chamber of horrors.
我的两个助手在打赌，受伤的人能承受多少疼痛
Two of my assistants were betting on the tolerance of an injured man,
要过多久才能让人昏厥
how long it would take him to pass out from the pain.
- 报告这里的技术情况 - 大部分变化都在仪表上
- Report on technology. - Mostly variations in instrumentation.
- 我都能应付 - 太空的情况呢？
- Nothing I can't handle. - Star readings?
一切都正常，除了我们
Everything's exactly where it should be, except us.
让我们查查我们在哪里吧
Let's find out where we stand.
- 计算机 - 准备就绪
- Computer. - Ready.
我是舰长，记录一项加密调查
This is the captain. Record security research
这项调查只有我或者史考特先生的语音才能解读
to be classified under my voiceprint or Mr. Scott's.
记录中
Recording.
记录下所有关于最近遭遇的电磁风暴的数据
Produce all data relevant to the recent ion storm.
考虑如下的假设：
Correlate the following hypothesis:
那种强度的风暴能不能
Could a storm of such magnitude cause a power surge
在传送室设备中产生能量
in the transporter circuits, creating a momentary
使人暂时和平行宇宙产生跨维度接触？
interdimensional contact with a parallel universe?
确认
Affirmative.
在那个时候，在各自宇宙的人
At such a moment, could persons in each universe,
能否通过传送
in the act of beaming, transpose with their counterparts
与另一宇宙的人换位？
in the other universe?
确认
Affirmative.
这种情况能否使用这艘船的能量
Could conditions necessary to such an event
人工制造出来？
be created artificially, using the ship's power?
确认
Affirmative.
记录下步骤
Record procedure.
史考特，你能做到吗？
Scotty, can you do it?
我一个人不行，我需要帮助
Not by myself. I'll need help.
你是舰长，太引人注意了
You'd be too conspicuous.
我是医生，不是工程师
I'm a doctor, not an engineer.
你现在是工程师了
Now you're an engineer.
我要先从曲速引擎中获取需要的能量
I'll have to tap the power we need from the warp engines
然后分成4等分
and balance it for the four of us.
吉姆，看这艘船管理这么混乱
Jim, the way this ship is run,
这个宇宙的我们是怎样的人？
what kind of people are we in this universe?
我们来查一查，计算机
Let's find out. Computer.
准备就绪
Ready.
报出现任指挥官的经历
Read out official record of current command.
舰长，詹姆士·T·寇克
Captain James T. Kirk.
通过谋杀舰长克里斯托弗·派克
Succeeded to command ISS Enterprise
成功控制ISS进取号
through assassination of Captain Christopher Pike.
第一次任务：镇压格兰星人起义
First action: Suppression of Gorlan uprising
摧毁了反叛者的母星
through destruction of rebel home planet.
第二次任务：在织女9行星处决了5000名殖民者
Second action: Execution of 5,000 colonists on Vega IX.
取消
Cancel.
- 现在我们了解了 - 舰长
- Now we know. - Captain.
- 我们能做到 - 好的
- We can do it. - Good.
我们必须把它设置成自动传送
We have to lay in the automatic-transporter setting.
但当我们打断引擎正常工作
But when we interrupt engine circuits
将能量导入到传送室时
to tie the power increase into the transporter,
苏鲁的安全面板上会显示出来
it'll show up on Sulu's security board.
当然，这只需要一点时间
Of course, we'll only need a second.
我会通知乌乎拉吸引苏鲁的注意力
I'll tell Uhura to create a diversion to distract Sulu's attention at your signal.
我们最好回到各自岗位，保持联络
We'd better get back to our posts. Keep me advised.
吉姆
Jim.
现在我们在这里，这个宇宙的我们
If we're here, what do you suppose our counterparts are doing
在我们的宇宙中在做什么呢？
back in our universe?
在我们的进取号上
On our Enterprise.
我命令你
I order you!
放开我
Let me go!
叛徒，史波克，让这些人放开我
Traitors! Spock, get these men off me!
史波克，你知道你在做什么吗？
What do you think you're doing, Spock?
你这个叛徒，我要吊起你的瓦肯耳朵
You traitorous pig. I'll hang you up by your Vulcan ears.
- 我一定要把你们都处决了 - 我可不这么想
- I'll have you all executed! - I think not.
舰长，你在这艘船上的权威非常有限
Your authority on this ship is extremely limited, captain.
你们四个要被监管在这件舱室里
The four of you will remain here in the brig, and in custody,
直到我想出把你们送回去的方法
until I discover how to return you to wherever it is you belong.
这整个星系都疯了吗？这算什么制服？
Has the whole galaxy gone crazy? What kind of a uniform is this?
你的胡子呢？发生了什么事？我的私人护卫呢？
Where's your beard? What's going on? Where's my personal guard?
现在我一个问题也回答不了你
I can answer none of your questions at this time.
好吧，史波克
All right, Spock.
不管你耍什么花样，我都奉陪
Whatever your game is, I'll play it.
你想要信贷吗？我会给你的，你会很有钱
You want credits? I'll give them to you. You'll be a rich man.
你想要自己的追随者？我也答应你
A command of your own? I can swing that too.
很显然，这里发生了某种换位
Apparently, some kind of transposition has taken place.
我发现这很有趣
I find it extremely interesting.
史波克，你到底想要什么？
Spock, what is it that will buy you?
- 权力？ - 有意思
- Power? - Fascinating.
你想要权力吗，史波克？我会给你的
Power, Spock? I can get that for you!
舰长
Captain.
我很高兴你没让契诃夫的计划得逞
I am pleased that you frustrated Mr. Chekov's plan.
如果你死了，我会很难过的
I should regret your death.
- 为什么？ - 我不想做舰长
- Why? - I do not desire the captaincy.
我更喜欢科学官的职位
I much prefer my scientific duties,
而且老实说，我不想成为一个显眼的目标
and I am, frankly, content to be a lesser target.
史波克，你还是那么有逻辑性
Logical, as always, Mr. Spock.
肉体电击是最有效的惩罚方法
The agony booth is a most effective means of discipline.
你已经下令给他最大强度的电击了？
I presume you've ordered full duration?
我还没决定
I haven't decided.
真的吗？
Indeed?
- 他的行为够判死刑了 - 我说过了，我还没决定
- His act warrants death. - I said, I haven't decided.
当然，这是你的事情
That is, of course, your affair.
舰长，我能问下你是否还坚持
Captain, may I enquire if you intend to persist
用反常的行为对待哈克星人？
in your unusual course of action regarding the Halkans?
你听到我的命令了
You heard my orders.
当然，你的命令不符合帝国的规范
They are, of course, in contradiction to standard Empire procedure.
你不能不考虑后果
You cannot ignore the consequences.
这是威胁吗？
Is that a threat?
我没有威胁你，舰长，我只是陈述事实
I do not threaten, captain. I merely state facts.
我一直觉得你是个优秀的长官
I have found you to be an excellent officer.
我们一起执行的任务都大获全胜，战绩斐然
Our missions together have been both successful and profitable.
然而我不会允许你反常的行为
However, I shall not permit your aberrations
危及到我的职位
to jeopardise my position.
史波克…
Spock...
…你觉得我们应该摧毁哈克星人吗？
...do you think we should destroy the Halkans?
暴力手段必须维持，不然帝国将会灭亡
Terror must be maintained, or the Empire is doomed.
- 这是历史的逻辑 - 征服容易，但是控制艰难
- It is the logic of history. - Conquest is easy. Control is not.
我们征服的太多，已经超出了控制的能力
We may have bitten off more than we can chew.
舰长，我不想反对你
Captain, I do not wish to find myself opposing you.
但是如果你继续像现在一样
But if you continue on your present course,
行事那么反常、令人费解…
this confusing, inexplicable behaviour...
这是我该担心的问题，不是你的
Is my concern, not yours.
你会发现我变成了强大的敌人
You would find me a formidable enemy.
我了解，舰长
I am aware of that, captain.
反过来，我相信你也了解我的实力
I trust that you are aware of the reverse.
长官，你有什么命令吗？
Orders, sir?
把契诃夫放了，把他关押在监视室里
Release Chekov. Confine him to quarters.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
这剂药能让他昏迷6个小时
That ought to hold him for about six hours.
我睡着了
I fell asleep.
风暴过后，我们花了很长时间收拾化学实验室
We had quite a time in the Chem Lab picking up after the storm.
我想，谁也比不上你今天过得精彩
Nothing compared to your day, I gather.
我听说契诃夫的事了
I heard about Chekov.
他铤而走险，我赢了
He gambled. I won.
你走运而已
You got lucky.
我很惊讶你脱离了警卫
I'm surprised that you could be caught off guard that way.
我掉以轻心了
I was preoccupied.
你和星舰司令部之间还有麻烦
You're still in trouble with Starfleet Command.
这次你心里想什么可难倒我了
What you've got in mind this time is beyond me.
当然，你有你的计划
You're scheming, of course.
哈克星上有你想要的东西
The Halkans have something you want.
或者这只是你进一步高升的台阶？
Or is it all some clever means to advance you to the admiralty?
寇克
Kirk.
- 你想进内阁吗？ - 远不止那个，如果我成功的话
- The cabinet itself? - Further than that, if I'm successful.
真的？
Really?
嗯，你一定知道自己在做什么
Well, you must know what you're doing.
你一向如此
You always do.
如果我要成为凯撒的女人…
If I'm to be the woman of a Caesar...
…我怎么会不知道你要干什么呢？
...can't I know what you're up to?
- 我是寇克 - 舰长，我是史波克
- Kirk here. - Mr. Spock, captain.
有什么事吗？
Yes?
我收到了星舰司令部发来的私人消息
I've received a private communication from Starfleet Command.
让你知道消息的内容
I am committing a breach of regulations
已经违反了规定
by informing you of its contents.
嗯，史波克
Yes, Mr. Spock?
我被告知，在阳光照射到主目标之前
I'm instructed to wait until planet dawn over principal target
我会允许你执行任务
to permit you to carry out our mission.
如果我不呢？
And if I don't?
如果那样的话，我被命令杀死你
In that event, I am ordered to kill you
作为进取号的新舰长，摧毁哈克星
and to proceed against the Halkans as the new captain of the Enterprise.
舰长日志，星历未知
Captain's log, stardate unknown.
我们被困在了一个野蛮的平行宇宙里
We are trapped in a savage parallel universe
在4个小时内我们必须逃离这里
from which we must escape within four hours
不然史波克就会杀掉我
or I will face a death sentence at Mr. Spock's hands.
让我们为史波克干杯
Let's drink a toast to Spock,
他是这艘船上唯一体面警告你的人
the only man aboard with the decency to warn you.
他会为此而死
And he'll die for it.
你再也找不到像他那样的人了
You'll never find another man like him.
我不会杀他
I don't intend to kill him.
你会在最后期限前对付哈克星人吗？
Are you going to act against the Halkans before the deadline?
不，但是我也会避免杀死史波克
No. But I'll avoid killing Spock.
你要让他不插手这件事？他和他的属下？
Just get him out of the way? He and his men?
我会让他不插手这件事的
I'll get out of his way.
需要我激活坦塔罗斯场吗？
Shall I activate the Tantalus field?
最起码你要监视他，是不是？
You'll at least want to monitor him, won't you?
是的
Yes.
我恨这个东西
I hate this thing.
- 也没那么坏 - 当然不，是它让你当上舰长的
- It's not that bad. - Of course not. It made you captain.
轻轻的按下按钮
How many enemies have you simply wiped out of existence
你靠这个消灭了多少敌人？
by the touch of a button?
50个？100个？
Fifty? A hundred?
我一直觉得这很滑稽
And I always thought that was funny.
伟大的、强大的寇克舰长
The great, powerful Captain Kirk, who owes everything
他的一切都是拜未知的外星科技所赐
to some unknown alien scientist and a plundered laboratory.
嗯，如果你不好好利用这机会…
Well, if you don't take advantage of your opportunities...
你不会成为舰长
You don't rise to the command of a starship.
或者更高的职位
Or even higher.
他的心肠很好
That magnificent mind of his.
但是这不能保护他免除伤害
But it can't protect him from this.
我按下这个按钮，他就会死
I press it, and he dies.
现在吗？
Now?
你真的要那样做
You really mean it.
没关系
It doesn't matter.
如果史波克没有遵守命令，无论如何都会被杀死
If Spock fails his order, he'll be killed anyway.
我要确保他不遵守命令也能保全自己
I'll see to it that the circumstances of his failure will clear him.
你甚至都不害怕星舰司令部
You're not even afraid of Starfleet Command.
你的计划能这么快得获得权力吗？
Can your scheme bring you that much power so quickly?
那我呢？玛丽安娜该如何自处呢？
And what about me? How does Marlena fit in?
玛丽安娜想要怎么自处呢？
How does Marlena want to fit in?
- 史考特 - 长官，我是史考特
- Scotty. - Scotty here, sir.
我们必须在3个小时内离开这里
We have to get out of here within three hours.
史波克已经得到命令，除非我执行任务，否则就要杀了我
Spock has orders to kill me unless I complete the military mission.
- 长官，我们这也遇到了一个最后期限 - 说明情况
- We've got another deadline too, sir. - Explain.
双路的物质传送
The two-way matter transmission
影响了宇宙中局部场密度
affected the local field density between the universes
而且一直在增加，我们必须要快速行动
and it's increasing. We've got to move fast.
- 要多快？ - 最多一个半小时
- How fast? - A half hour, at the most.
如果我们赶不及呢？
If we miss?
我们永远也不能离开这里了
We couldn't get out of here in a century.
我们准备连通引擎和传送室，传导能量了
Now, we're ready to bridge power from the engines to the transporter.
你要下来设置控制面板，这样我们才能连接到传送室
You've got to get down there and free the board so we can lock in.
给我十分钟时间
Give me about ten minutes.
我还要完成一些计算
I've gotta complete a few more computations.
好的，我会在10分钟内到传送室
All right, I'll be in the Transporter Room in ten minutes.
- 稍后我会在医务室和你汇合 - 好的，长官
- I'll meet you in the Sickbay afterward. - Aye, sir.
- 计算机 - 准备就绪
- Computer. - Ready.
解释下工程部计算机的动态
Explain computer activity in the Engineering section.
一项加密调查正在运行
A security research is in progress.
谁在做调查？
Who is conducting the research?
舰长和史考特先生
The captain and Mr. Scott.
这项调查的内容是什么？
What is the nature of the research?
这项调查已经被语音加密
Program is classified under voice-index lock.
苏鲁先生，你为什么要监视我的通话？
Why are you monitoring my communications, Mr. Sulu?
史波克先生，我的监控板监测到计算机活动
My security board has detected extensive use of computer, Mr. Spock.
我正要通知你
I was about to inform you.
要猜出你收到的星舰司令部命令的内容并不难
It's not hard to guess the nature of your order from Starfleet Command.
我猜，舰长被怀疑了
I suggest a connection, the captain suspects.
他想要逃跑或者叛变
He's working on escape or defence.
那是我该考虑的问题
That is my concern.
当然了，这是你的事情，我希望你能赢
Correct, it's your play. I hope you succeed,
因为同样的命令下一次就会发给我了
because the order would fall on me next.
而且你要知道寇克舰长的敌人…
And you know how Captain Kirk's enemies have a habit of...
…最后都失踪了
...disappearing.
如果我成功了，你也会更接近舰长头衔
If I am successful, you see yourself a step nearer to the captaincy.
我不想领导进取号
I do not want to command the Enterprise.
但是如果责任落到我身上
But if it should befall me,
我建议你记住
I suggest you remember
我的追随者会为我复仇的
that my operatives would avenge my death.
而他们中间有些人
And some of them
是瓦肯人
are Vulcans.
亲爱的，来给我的背擦油
Oiling my traps, darling.
我担心，我有点表现失常了
I'm afraid I'm a little out of practise.
或许这就是我们之间的感情
Maybe that's what happened to us.
让一个女船员每时每刻 都像一个女人那样光鲜耀眼真的很难
It's very hard for a working officer to shine as a woman every minute.
- 而你苛求完美 - 我从没见过完美的事物
- And you demand perfection. - I've never seen perfection.
但是没有任何女人比你更接近完美了
But no woman could come closer to it.
我还记得你过去说这些话的样子
I remember when you used to talk that way.
- 我依然未变 - 那就证明它
- I still do. - Prove it.
- 我要走了 - 船上的事务吗？
- I've gotta go. - Ship's business?
要在甲板上宣布一项重要任务？
An important task on the crew deck?
嗯，我想我们之间完了
Well, I guess it's over.
指挥官肯尼会带我走，他已经说得很明白了
Commander Kenner will take me temporarily. He's made that quite clear.
我会找个仆人帮我收拾东西
I'll call a yeoman to help me with my things.
你不必那么做
You don't have to do that.
你对我感到歉疚吗？
Are you feeling sorry for me?
我在你的眼中可曾看到过犹豫？
Do I see hesitation in your eyes, about anything?
舰长，我只想要一件事：
I want one thing, captain:
传送我
Transfer me.
在进取号上，我被羞辱了
On the Enterprise, I am humiliated.
在另一艘船上，我可以重新开始
On another ship, I can hunt fresh game.
我已经得到了官衔，并且…
I've got my rank, and...
难道不是吗？
Don't I?
我曾经是一个舰长的女人，我喜欢那种感觉
I've been a captain's woman and I like it.
我会再次成为舰长的女人，即使我要走遍整个舰队
I'll be one again, if I have to go though every officer in the fleet.
你可以的
You could.
我只是想说…
I simply meant...
…你可以做你想要成为的任何人
...that you could be anything you want to be.
你好长时间没有像那样吻我了
It's been a long time since you've kissed me like that.
你不是寇克
You're a stranger.
你同情哈克星人，同情史波克
Mercy to the Halkans, mercy to Spock,
同情我
to me.
我是你的女人吗？
Am I your woman?
除非你拒绝，你一直是舰长的女人
You're the captain's woman until he says you're not.
乌乎拉
Uhura.
是的，舰长
Yes, captain.
史考特的信号随时都可能发出
Scotty's signal should be coming through any moment now.
- 你知道该怎么做 - 长官，我有一个好主意
- You know what to do. - I've got a pretty good idea, sir.
转移苏鲁的注意力，不让他盯着监控板
Keep Sulu's attention off that board.
长官，我会尽力的
I'll do my best, sir.
祝好运，通话结束
Good luck. Kirk out.
苏鲁先生，你没有坚持
You aren't very persistent, Mr. Sulu.
游戏都是有规则的，你忽视了他们
The game has rules. You're ignoring them.
我拒绝了，你要再追求我
I protest, and you come back.
你没有继续追求
You didn't come back.
- 你现在终于开窍了 - 我很无聊
- Now you're making sense. - I was getting bored.
当然了，现在这个时间不合适
Of course, this isn't the time.
任何时间都是合适的
Any time's a good time.
恐怕我又改变主意了
I'm afraid I changed my mind again.
上尉，你错过了很多次机会
You take a lot of chances, lieutenant.
你也是，先生
So do you, mister.
你也是
So do you.
接替我的工作
Take over for me.
史考特先生
Mr. Scott.
一切正常，我正在去医务室的路上
All clear. On my way to Sickbay.
现在就看舰长的了
Now it's up to the captain.
舰长，你的行动应该受到限制
You will please restrict your movements, captain.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
史波克，你现在要开枪吗？我还以为可以等到黎明
Are you gonna shoot me now, Spock? I thought I had until dawn.
我做了决定
I shall make that decision.
自从你从哈克星上回来
Since you returned from the planet,
你就表现地极其反常
you have behaved in a most atypical and illogical manner.
- 我想知道原因 - 开枪吧，你在浪费时间
- I want to know why. - Shoot. You're wasting time.
我不会和你浪费时间
I shall not waste time with you.
一旦你下定决定，你就会变得太遵守纪律，顽固不懂变通
You're too inflexible, too disciplined, once you've made up your mind.
但是麦考伊医生有着丰富的人性缺点
But Dr. McCoy has a plenitude of human weaknesses.
敏感，性格软弱
Sentimental, soft.
你或许不会告诉我真相
You may not tell me what I want to know,
但是他会的
but he will.
史波克，你这是冒险
You're running a big risk, Spock.
舰长，我带着手枪
I have the phaser, captain.
而且我也不想
And I do not intend to simply disappear
像过去你的对手一样莫名其妙地失踪
as so many of your opponents have in the past.
如果你愿意
If you please.
到医务室去
Sickbay.
哦，当然了，整个登陆队伍都到齐了
Yes, of course. The entire landing party.
舰长，站到那边去
Captain, stand over there.
医生，是时候告诉我真相了
Doctor, it is time for answers.
史考特，还有多少时间？
How much time, Scotty?
不到15分钟了，长官
Hardly 15 minutes, sir.
两个宇宙之间的场密度
The field density between the two universes
开始要关闭了，速度很快
is starting to close very fast.
帮我把他抬到床上
Help me get him on the table.
快点，帮我把他抬到床上
Come on, help me get him on the table!
如果不及时治疗，他会死的
He'll die without immediate treatment.
史考特，都准备好了吗？
Everything laid in, Scotty?
操作时间间隔有没有设好？ 让操作的人能有时间进到传送室
The time lag, so the operator can get into the transporter chamber?
长官，都准备好了
All laid in, sir.
来吧，麦考伊
Come on, McCoy
你这么做我们可能都回不了家了
we're taking a chance on not getting back home.
我们会回家的，这不需要很长时间
We'll get home. This won't take long.
还剩14分钟，我们一定要走
Fourteen minutes. We've got to go!
你闭嘴
You shut up!
我能救他
I can save his life.
吉姆，你不希望我救他吗？
Do you want me to stop, Jim?
这花不了多少时间
It'll only take a minute.
他和我们的史波克很像，是不是？
He is very much like our own Mr. Spock, isn't he?
好吧，给你时间救他
You've got that minute.
只需要一点时间，他就能活过来
A little time, he'll live.
苏鲁，你这是要做什么？
What is this, Mr. Sulu?
舰长，史波克先生下令要杀你
Mr. Spock has orders to kill you, captain.
他会继任舰长
He will succeed.
但显然，在经过激烈的搏斗之后…
Apparently, you will also appear to have killed him...
…你已经杀了他
...after a fierce battle.
很遗憾，但最后是我掌权了
Regrettable, but it will leave me in command.
舰长，我们只有10分钟了
Captain, we've barely got ten minutes.
我们走，老骨头
Let's go, Bones.
吉姆，我不能让他死
I can't let him die, Jim.
你们去传送室，做好准备
You get to the Transporter Room, make sure it's clear.
- 五分钟内我会到那里的 - 你只有五分钟时间
- I'll be there in five minutes. - No longer.
我保证
I guarantee it.
好吧，我们走
Now, go on, please.
为什么舰长没杀死我？
Why did the captain let me live?
医生，我们的思维在融合
Our minds are merging, doctor.
我们的思维合二为一
Our minds are one.
我能感受到你的感受
I feel what you feel.
我能知道你的事情
I know what you know.
她是我的朋友
A friend.
激活传送器
Activate the transporter.
你在医务室用坦塔罗斯场救了我
You saved us back in Sickbay, with the Tantalus field.
- 带我走吧 - 我不能
- Take me with you. - I can't.
抱歉，能量最多能分4份
I'm sorry. Our power's balanced for four.
分成5份时就不能保证了，我们可能都会死
There's no guarantee we'll make it with five. All could die.
- 史考特？ - 工作正常，长官
- Scotty? - It's working, sir.
- 但是你们只有三个人 - 最后一个正在赶来
- But there are only three of you. - One is coming.
玛丽安娜，我真的很想帮你
I'd help you if I could, Marlena. Believe that.
你杀了我们，也不能离开这里
If you kill us, you'll still stay.
麦考伊在哪里？
Where's McCoy?
- 还有多少时间，史考特？ - 长官，还有5分钟
- Time, Scotty? - Five minutes, sir.
你知道他们会怎么对我吗？
Do you know what they'll do to me?
长官，电力中断了，他们发现我们了
The power is cut, sir. They're on to us!
- 辅助电力呢？ - 辅助电力可以使用
- Auxiliary? - Aye, it's available.
你能直接把能量传到传输室吗？
Can you bridge to your setup?
我能把能量传送过来
I can get us the power,
但是自动设置是连接到传输室主电源的
but the automatic setting is linked to the transporter main.
如果我们绕过自动设置
If we bypass,
那就意味着需要某个人手动操作控制台
it means that someone has got to operate the controls manually.
我们中有人必须留下
One of us will have to stay.
舰长，我留下吧
I'll stay, captain.
到传输室去，乌乎拉，你也是
Get to the transporter chamber. You too, Uhura.
吉姆
Jim.
史考特，这是命令
That's an order, Scotty.
是，舰长
Aye, captain.
那我呢？
What about me?
麦考伊…
McCoy...
我切断了传输室的能量
I cut the transporter power.
这样我才能赶上你们
It was necessary to delay your beam-out until I could arrive.
工程部，将主传输室电路复位
Engineering, reactivate main transporter circuits.
史波克，你在两个宇宙中都是那么正直
You're a man of integrity in both universes, Mr. Spock.
你必须回到你的宇宙中去，我必须让我的舰长回来
You must return to your universe, I must have my captain back.
我来操作传送装置
I'll operate the transporter.
你还剩2分10秒
You have two minutes and ten seconds.
在走之前，我有一些话要说
For that time, I have something to say.
哈克星人预言的起义什么时候出现？
How long before the Halkan prediction of galactic revolt is realised?
- 大约240年之后 - 不可避免的结果是什么？
- Approximately 240 years. - The inevitable outcome?
当然是帝国被推翻
The Empire shall be overthrown, of course.
史波克先生，这期间的浪费是不合逻辑的
The illogic of waste, Mr. Spock.
生命、资源、时间的浪费
The waste of lives, potential resources, time.
我告诉你，你的帝国的存在是不合逻辑的
I submit to you that your Empire is illogical
因为它不能持续
because it cannot endure. I submit...
…你乐意成为其中的一员也是不合逻辑的
...that you are illogical to be a willing part of it.
你还有1分23秒
You have one minute and 23 seconds.
如果改变是不可避免的，可预测的，有益的
If change is inevitable, predictable, beneficial,
你成为其中一员难倒不合逻辑吗？
doesn't logic demand that you be a part of it?
一个人无法改变未来…
One man cannot summon the future...
但可以改变现在
But one man can change the present.
史波克，做这艘进取号的舰长吧
Be the captain of this Enterprise, Mr. Spock.
找一个合乎逻辑的原因放过哈克星，把它作为基地
Find a logical reason for sparing the Halkans, and make it stick.
推动革命直到帝国放弃
Push till it gives.
你可以变得比司令部任何人都强大
You can defend yourself better than any man in the fleet.
舰长，快进传送室
Captain, get in the chamber!
史波克，你觉得怎么样呢？
What about it, Spock?
那个人还需要别的力量
The man must also have the power.
在我的船舱里
In my cabin
有一种东西能让你变得无法战胜
is a device that will make you invincible.
- 真的吗？ - 那会是什么呢？
- Indeed? - What will it be?
过去或未来，暴政或自由，都取决于你
Past or future? Tyranny or freedom? It's up to you.
你们该走了
It is time.
在每一场革命中，都需要一个有远见的人
In every revolution, there is one man with a vision.
寇克舰长，我会考虑的
Captain Kirk, I shall consider it.
- 史波克 - 舰长，欢迎回家
- Spock. - Welcome home, captain.
我不明白你怎么会
What I don't understand is how you were able
那么快地分辨出另一个宇宙中的我们
to identify our counterparts so quickly.
你们作为文明人，想要表现的野蛮
It was far easier for you, as civilised men, to behave like barbarians
要比他们作为野蛮人表现得文明，容易得多
than it was for them, as barbarians, to behave like civilised men.
我认为在你出现在这里的时候
I assume they returned to their Enterprise
他们也回到了他们的进取号
at the same time you appeared here?
或许吧，然而，那个吉姆·寇克会发现一些改变
Probably. However, that Jim Kirk will find a few changes,
如果我真正了解了另一个宇宙的史波克
if I read my Spocks correctly.
吉姆，我觉得我更喜欢他有胡子的样子
Jim, I think I liked him with a beard better.
让他更有个性
Gave him character.
当然了，几乎任何改变都有好处
Of course, almost any change would be a distinct improvement.
更让我担心的是
What worries me is the easy way
另一个宇宙的史波克那么轻易的就融入了群体
his counterpart fitted into that other universe.
我一直觉得史波克内心有一点海盗情节
I always thought Spock was a bit of a pirate at heart.
确实，先生们，我也要指出我有机会
Indeed, gentlemen. May I point out that I had opportunity
密切关注另一个宇宙中的你们
to observe your counterparts here quite closely.
他们残酷、野蛮、没有原则、未开化
They were brutal, savage, unprincipled, uncivilised, treacherous.
从任何角度看，都是未进化人类的杰出代表
In every way, splendid examples of homo sapiens,
人类中的奇葩
the very flower of humanity.
我发现他们很不一样
I found them quite refreshing.
似乎我觉得我们被侮辱了
I'm not sure, but I think we've been insulted.
我确定
I'm sure.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk?
- 上尉…你叫什么名字？ - 玛丽安娜·梦露
- Lieutenant... Lieutenant? - Marlena Moreau.
我上周刚被分配到进取号上
I was just assigned last week.
好的，上尉，继续工作吧
All right, lieutenant. Carry on.
舰长，以前见过她吗？
Met her before, captain?
你为什么会这么问？
Why do you ask?
你的反应，像是认识她的样子
Your reaction. One of recognition?
哦，没有，我们从前没见过…
Oh, no. No, no, we haven't met before...
…实际上
...exactly.
她看起来像一个漂亮、可爱的女孩
She just seemed a nice, likeable girl.
我想我们能成为朋友
I think we could become friends.
这很可能
It's possible.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/